(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T12:27:11.913830",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
キミのココロの中を全部見せてよ
Show me everything inside your heart.
何がスキで何がキライでボクはどのくらいかな？
What do you like, what do you hate, and how much do you care for me?
今日はどんな服着てどこで何をしてるの？
What kind of clothes are you wearing today, and what are you doing and where?
全部全部隠さないでいいよボクに教えて？
Don't hide anything at all, tell me everything!
経験なんて気にしない！偏見ばっかりだらない！
Don't mind experience! No prejudice!
期待しない！なんて嘘ばかり
"I don't expect anything!" is just a lie.
顔色窺い胃がキリキリ
Reading your face, my stomach is twisting.
一人で踊れば良いでしょ独りじゃ眠れない
Dancing alone is fine, but I can't sleep by myself.
ずっと欲しかった言葉も
Even the words I always wanted...
素面のままだいじゅーで出てこないなら
won't come out straight and sober.
3つ数えて世界が止まればいいのに
Count to three and let the world stop already.
モウモドレナイ
I can't go back anymore.
触れて溶け合うくらいの距離感で
At a distance where we touch and melt into each other,
ボクのことだけ見ててよ
just look at me.
跡をつけてよ消えないくらいに
Leave a mark, enough so it won't fade away.
ほらねえまいぎゅっとしてきて
Come on, hold me tight like my  Myu.
曖昧だっていいよなんてボクは理解するから
I understand that ambiguity is fine too,
気付かないフリしてあげるって
pretending not to notice.
だからねえまい好きって言ってよ
So come on, tell me "Myu, I love you."
好きって言ってよ
Say that you love me!
冗談じゃないよ？
It's not a joke, you know?
キミの居ない未来なんて全部いらない！
A future without you is completely useless!
触れて溶け合うくらいの距離感で
At a distance where we touch and melt into each other,
ボクのことだけ見ててよ
just look at me.
痕をつけてよ消えないくらいに
Leave a trace, enough so it won't fade away.
ほらねえまいぎゅっとしてきて
Come on, hold me tight like my Myu.
何回だっていいよなんてボクは理解するから
No matter how many times is fine, I understand,
気付かないフリしてあげるって
pretending not to notice.
だからねえまい好きって言ってよ
So come on, tell me "Myu, I love you."
好きって言ってよ
Say that you love me!
キミのココロの中を全部見せてよ
Show me everything inside your heart.
何がスキで何がキライでボクはどのくらいかな？
What do you like, what do you hate, and how much do you care for me?
今日はどんな服着てどこで何をしてるの？
What kind of clothes are you wearing today, and what are you doing and where?
全部全部隠さないでいいよボクに教えて？
Don't hide anything at all, tell me everything!
経験なんて気にしない！偏見ばっかりだらない！
Don't mind experience! No prejudice!
期待しない！なんて嘘ばかり
"I don't expect anything!" is just a lie.
顔色窺い胃がキリキリ
Reading your face, my stomach is twisting.
眠れない
I can't sleep,
ずっと欲しかった言葉も白昼夢のまま捨ててこないなら
if you're not going to throw away the words I've always wanted as a daydream.
見つかぞえて
Counting them up,
世界が止まれば
if the world were to stop,
いいのに
that would be nice.
触れ合って溶け合うくらいの距離感でね
At a distance where we touch and melt,
僕のことだけ見てってよ 後付けってよ
look only at me, remember that.
消えないくらいにほらね 今
So it won't fade away, look, now
ぎゅってして 曖昧だっていいよなんて
hold me tight, even ambiguity is fine.
僕は分かるから 気づかないふりしてあげるって
Because I understand, I'll pretend not to notice,
だからね 今 好きって言ってよ
so now, say you love me.
好きって言ってよ
Say you love me.
永遠なんてありゃしない
There's no such thing as forever,
健全なんて嘘ばかり
wholesomeness is just a pack of lies.
期待したいなんて嘘ばかり 顔色伺いもきりきり
Wanting to expect things is a lie, anxiously reading expressions endlessly.
一人でなきゃいけない
I have to be alone,
でも一人じゃ笑えない
but alone, I can't smile.
ずっと欲しかった言葉も 表のまま捨ててこないなら
If you're not going to leave behind the words I've always wanted openly,
見つかぞえて
counting them up,
世界が変われば
if the world changes,
いいのに
that would be nice.
ガラガラ堂々立ててく 崩れる景色の中 落ちてく見つけ出してよ
Standing tall and proud, falling through the collapsing scenery, find me.
離れないくらいにほらね
So we won't part, look, now
今 ぎゅってして 何回だっていいよなんて
hold me tight now, however many times is fine.
僕は分かるから
Because I understand,
いつか最後に引きずれるってだからね
someday we can drag it out to the end, so
また 好きって言ってよ
say you love me again.
夜が明けるまで 話を聞いて
Listen to me talk until dawn breaks,
終わらない夢みたいに 輝いてみせた
shining like an endless dream.
どうか 今だけ さめないで
Please, don't wake up just yet.
譲るんじゃないよ 君のいない明日なんて全部いらない
Don't yield, I don't need any tomorrow without you.
ずっと一緒だよね
We'll always be together, right?
触れ合って溶け合うくらいの 距離感でね 僕のことだけ見てってよ
At a distance where we touch and melt, look only at me,
後付けってよ
remember that.
消えないくらいにほらね 今 ぎゅってして
So it won't fade, look, hold me tight now,
何回だっていいよなんて 僕は分かるから 気づかないふりしてあげるって
however many times is fine, because I understand and will pretend not to notice.
だからね 今 好きって言ってよ 好きって言ってよ
So now, say you love me, say you love me.
灰のない 深い影ばかり
Fire-deprived, deep shadows only,
愛のない 個体 ドールみたい
a loveless individual, like a doll.
自分 不在 どこにもいない ないじゃない
Self absent, nowhere to be found, aren't I?
曖昧な愛 色のない愛 期待 意外 人ごとみたい お陰様 どちら様
Ambiguous love, colorless love, expectations, acting like it's not my problem.
何者でもないまま 何にもできないまま 生きる態度は無駄ですか？ 悪いことですか？
Remaining nobody, unable to do anything, is living like this useless? Is it wrong?
自分 自分 誰も見ない 見ない 見ないまま
Myself, myself, no one looks, leaving me unseen.
掃き捨ててさようならなら
If you're just going to throw me away and say goodbye,
嬉しくない 悲しくもない 透明な気分
I'm neither happy nor sad, just a transparent mood.
足りない自分 合わす顔もない
An inadequate self, with no face to show.
空っぽなまま ああ ああ ああ 自分を殺して 笑うのはやめて
Staying empty, ah, stop killing yourself and smiling.
「生きていていいんだよ」なんて そんなの嘘だとわかっている
"It's okay to live," and things like that—I know are lies.
ここにはいない いない いない 自分 自分
I'm not here, not here, myself, myself,
誰も見ない 見ない 見ないまま
no one looks, leaving me unseen.
掃き捨ててさようならなら
If you're just going to throw me away and say goodbye,
嬉しくない 悲しくもない 透明な気分
I'm neither happy nor sad, just a transparent mood.
足りない自分 合わす顔もない
An inadequate self, with no face to show.
笑えないじゃない
Can't you smile?
入れない ない ない 閉ざしたままの
Can't enter, no, no, staying locked away,
ゲンセイナンデ 期待だけダイ イヤイヤナゲラレタサイ てめえは知らない
worldly life is just full of expectations, unwanted dice thrown away, you don't know.
今 好きって言ってよ 夜が明けるまで 話を聞いて
Now, say you love me, listen to my stories until dawn breaks.
終わらない夢みたいに 輝いてみせた
Shining like an endless dream.
どうか 今だけ さめないで
Please, don't wake up just yet.
譲るんじゃないよ 君のいない明日なんて全部いらない
Don't yield, I don't need any tomorrow without you.
自分 自分 味わい 苦い 苦い
Myself, myself, tasting the bitterness.
灰のない 深い影ばかり
Deep shadows without ashes
愛のない 個体 ドールみたい
An individual without love, like a doll
自分 不在 どこにもいない
I am not here, I am not anywhere
ないじゃない？
It's not here, right?
曖昧な愛 色のない愛
A vague love, a colorless love
期待以外！他人事みたい
Unexpected! Feels like someone else's business
お陰様？
Thanks to you?
どちら様？
Who are you?
応え様々
So many different answers
何者でもないままで
Still a nobody, unable to do anything
何にもできないままで
Still unable to do anything
生きるのは無駄ですか？
Does that make living meaningless?
悪いことですか？
Is there something wrong with that?
ここにいないいないいないのは
Not here, not here, not here because...
そうだっていいじゃない
It's okay if it's like that, right?
ここにいないいないいないのは 自分 自分
Not here, not here, not here because, I, I
誰も見ない見ない見ないまま
Don't look at anyone, not looking, not looking as I
掃き捨ててさようならなら
Sweep things away and say goodbye
嬉しくない 悲しくない
Neither happy nor sad
透明な気分
A translucent feeling
足りない自分 合う顔もない 笑えないじゃない？
I feel like I'm deficient... It's not even funny, right?
かげもかたちも いっそなくしてしまえばいい
Shadows and forms, why not just do away with them
また灰ひとつ ひとつから始めればいい
With just ashes, again, start from scratch
ハイじゃない私 閉じたまま貝
I'm not high, clammed shut
返答 \"ハイ\" 期待だけ大
I answer 'yes', anticipations are high
嫌々投げられた骰
The die has been cast reluctantly
出目は知らない
Don't know which number will come up
ここにいたいいたいいたいいたいタイのもう
Want to stay here, stay here, stay here—that's...
自分 自分
Me, me
味は苦い苦い苦いまま
Tastes bitter, bitter, bitter all the while
当て所無いそうなら
Say goodbye, though I've no place to turn to
帰らない 行き先もない 迷子の気分
Won't go back, no place to go, feel lost
間違えてない？ まだ分からない
Have I made a mistake? Still don't know
どうだっていいじゃない
Who cares?
かげもかたちも いっそなくしてしまえばいい
Shadows and forms, why not just do away with them
また灰ひとつ ひとつから始めればいい
With just ashes, again, start from scratch
ここにいないいないいないのは
Not here, not here, not here because...
自分 自分 誰も見ない見ない見ないまま
I, I. Don't look at anyone, not looking
掃き捨ててさようならなら
Sweep away and say goodbye
嬉しいくらい悲しくもない
Neither happy nor sad
透明な気分
A translucent feeling
足りない自分 合う顔もない 笑えないじゃない？
I feel like I'm deficient... It's not even funny, right?
ここにいないいないいないのは 自分 自分
Not here, not here, not here because, I, I
ここにいたい（いたい）いたい（いたい）
Not here, not here, stay here
笑いたいじゃない？
I want to be able to laugh, right?
はーい！というわけで来てくれてありがとう！改めてこんばんは！
Hii! Thanks for coming! Good evening once again!
ハロー！ホロライブ所属ゼロ期生、ロボ子さんです！
Hello! I am Roboco, 0th generation of Hololive!
ロボ子生誕祭のロボ子だよー！今日は私の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
It's Roboco's birthday! Thank you for coming to my birthday live today!
え、もう高性能はてなみたいなコメント拾わないからね？だってもう今日9歳！
Eh, I'm not picking up comments like "high-performance my foot", you know? Because I'm turning 9 today!
主役！あ、やべえ、もう誕生日の答え質問しようと思ったのに言っちゃった！
The star of the show! Ah, crap, I was gonna ask you guys what my birthday answer is, but I blurted it out!
はーい！そう、ロボ子なんと今年で9歳になりました！9歳ー！
That's right, Roboco turned 9 years old this year! 9 years old!
呼ばない？来年もうふたけたになる、やばい、やばすぎる！わくわくしてきた！最後の一桁楽しんでいきたいと思います！
"Not calling me?" Next year I'll be in double digits, that's crazy, super crazy! I'm getting excited! I want to enjoy this last single-digit year!
はい、というわけで本日のハッシュタグを紹介します！じゃじゃん、本日のハッシュタグは、あ、こっちだった。えーロボ子爆誕2025ですね、みなさん見えましたか？
Hii, so with that, let me introduce today's hashtag! Tada, today's hashtag is... ah, it was this one. Uh, #RobocoBirth2025, right? Did everyone see it?
きっとなんか高性能な君たちだったらもうロボ子爆誕2025をつけてつぶやいていることでしょう！はい、たくさん私の可愛いスクショとともにポストしていってくださいね！こうして人は循環していくんですよ、ポストと。
I'm sure you high-performance folks are already tweeting with #RobocoBirth2025! Yes, please post lots of them along with my cute screenshots! This is how people circulate, with posts.
はい、というわけでまずは今日ね、えー私のオリジナル曲ビズラブから始まってないないを歌ったんですけど、どうでしたか？ビズラブ、ビズラブのMVと同じでね、ウルフカットじゃなくて通常の強そうなロングのやつでモキモキで行ったんですけど、え、どうだった？よかった？
Hii, so first off today, uh, we started with my original song "Water Me" and then sang "Nai Nai", how was it? "Water Me", just like the MV for "Water Me", instead of a wolf cut, I went with my usual strong-looking long hair, but... uh, how was it? Was it good?
え、そのなんかもう久しぶりだよね、この、このナイティドレスとかも。ウルフカットなんて初めてじゃない？ショートカット、ショート動画でしか撮らないからね。そう、セクシーでしょ？そして……
Eh, it's been a while, hasn't it, wearing this, this nighty dress and all. Isn't this my first time with a wolf cut? Because I only shoot short hair in short videos. Right, sexy? And...
ステージがなんかすごいかっこいい！え、かっこよすぎる！ふーん、今回はこんな感じなんですね！今日かなんか色々楽しみなことがいっぱいありそうだけど、え、一体なんで今日このステージなんだろうな？うーん。なんとあとでね、おー、
The stage is, like, super cool! Eh, too cool! Hmm, so this is what it's like this time! There seems to be a lot of fun things ahead today, but eh, why on earth is it this stage today? Hmm. Apparently later on, oh—
ロボ子がいるらしいんですけども、
Apparently, Roboco's around somewhere, but...
コメントにいないロボ子がいるらしくてですね、
I heard there's a Roboco who isn't in the comments...
気になった方は探してみてくださいね。
If you're curious, try looking for her.
いるかな？
Is she here?
うん。
Hmm.
あれ？ロボ子いるかな？
Huh? Is Roboco here?
あれ？いるかな？
Huh? Is she here?
きっと目が……見つけてるやつ多い。
She must have... a lot of people are finding her.
あ、正解、正解、ここにいます！
Ah, correct, correct, she's right here!
特等席、お前はいったい誰だったんだー！
Best seat in the house—just who on earth were you?!
ずっと私のことリハ中も見守ってくれてさ、ロボ子可愛いね。
You've been watching over me the whole time during rehearsal, Roboco is so cute.
はい、というわけで今日は誕生日のためにいっぱい、いっぱい、みんな、そして僕が楽しめる歌をたくさんね、ご用意いたしましたので、
Yes, so today for my birthday, I've prepared lots and lots of songs that everyone and I can enjoy together,
いっぱいレッスンもしたので楽しんでいってください！
and I've practiced a lot, so please enjoy!
はい、このあとはそろそろ一人でも歌うと思うんだけど、ゲストも呼んで歌っちゃおうかなと思います。
Yes, after this, I think I'll be singing alone soon, but I thought I'd invite some guests to sing along too.
最初は誰だろうな？
Who will it be first?
なんかすっごいキスいっぱいしたい気分になってきた、なんでだろう？
I feel like giving tons of kisses all of a sudden, why is that?
なんてだろ、うーん、チュチュチュ、チュ、チュチュチュチュチュチュチュ
Why is that? Hmm, chu chu chu, chu, chu chu chu chu chu chu chu...
モエちゃっかファイア 作詞・作曲：式部
[Song: Moechakka Fire / Lyrics & Music: Shikibu]
ようこそお越しなさっさいご主人様
Welcome, master, so glad you could come today!
隣に座ってせーの
Sit right next to me, ready, set—
萌え萌え萌え萌え
Moe moe moe moe!
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who's gonna be happy with this?
ねえ教えて笑顔でup pull pull
Hey, tell me, smiling, up pull pull!
愛想を忘れてご苦労様
Thanks for your hard work dropping the pleasantries
私とあなたでせーの
You and me, ready, set—
luv luv luv luv
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who's gonna be happy with this?
ねえ教えて笑顔でup pull pull
Hey, tell me, smiling, up pull pull!
ひらりはらりおなのごし
Fluttering by, little maiden
ふわりふわり言葉のそう
Softly floating words, yeah
それってつまらお冷な娘
That makes you a boring, cold girl
感情的リアル笑顔でup pull pull
With an emotional, real smile, up pull pull!
人波に寄るもの
Things drifting with the crowds
嘘を嘘で見抜けない
Can't see through lies as lies
しきしかな袖裾の皮
Sleeves and hems of leather skin
あー鳥肌
Ah, goosebumps
鵙肌
Shrike skin
アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Un deux trois!
まちがえたご指名を出しますああ
You've got the wrong reservation, ah—
私とあなたでせーの
You and me, ready, set—
luv luv luv luv
これは度派手にご苦労様
Thanks for your flashy hard work
あそびましょう笑顔でup brrrt brrrt
Let's play, smiling, up brrrt brrrt!
ひらりはらりここはどこ
Fluttering by, where is this?
ふわりふわり掃討let me show
Softly clearing out, let me show
それってつまらお冷な娘
That makes you a boring, cold girl
確証的リアル笑顔でup brrrt brrrt
With a confirmed, real smile, up brrrt brrrt!
歌い出す 秘密の鐘
The secret bell begins to ring
終わることのないこの世界
In this world that never ends
悲しい子供は
A sad child...
眠らせて おままごと
Let them sleep, playing house
あそびましょう笑顔でup pull pull
Let's play, smiling, up pull pull!
ひらりはらりおなのごし
Fluttering by, little maiden
ふわりふわり言葉のそう
Softly floating words, yeah
それってつまらお冷な娘
That makes you a boring, cold girl
感情的リアル笑顔でup pull pull
With an emotional, real smile, up pull pull!
あそびましょう笑顔でup pull pull
Let's play, smiling, up pull pull!
up pull pull
G4L 作詞：q*Left 作曲：Giga
[Song: G4L / Lyrics: q*Left, Music: Giga]
あれが正解なんて
Saying that's the correct answer...
誰の成れの果て？
Whose end result is that?
答えも欲しいのも一個でこれだけ 悩んだってしようがないじゃないで
I just want one answer, no point worrying about it!
あれは夢だったってことにしといて
Let's just pretend that was all a dream
でも全然思えないんだけど 助けてフォロワー！
But I can't think that at all, help me, followers!
抗うだけ 弱さの負け next, next lucky, lucky & lucky!
Just resisting, weakness loses, next, next lucky, lucky & lucky!
oh-eh-oh 割り切れたらさ oh-eh-oh 楽ななのにとか まださ、メイクストロング
oh-eh-oh If we could just accept it, oh-eh-oh It'd be so much easier...
ラキラキラキー
Lucky, lucky, lucky!
ありよ 割り切れたらさ おーりよ
Ario, if we could just accept it, oh-ly-oh!
I took my last delusions behind
Still, you're creeping through my thoughts tonight
Now, I know it's only skin deep
Drawn like a moth to a flame inside your heat, heat, heat
Considered myself fine,
but I'm crossing every line
Drunk on love that's not mine
Heaven sent you way too late, kiss of death and take the bait
Past lies and loaded dice, white lies and alibis
Fingers tracing edge of sin, a medicine I never swallowed right
Still no enemy to fight, not in this light
Stolen whispers, don't ask and don't tell
Step in my world, and welcome to hell
We fall, we break, we drown in fire
Lost inside in this dark desire
No love, no faith, just you and i
Dancing 'til the end of time, da-la-la-la-la-la, la-la-la
Da-la-la-la-la-la, la-la-la
I still blame myself for this hate
Shame that overflows and never dissipates
I let words unsaid rot slowly, tainted and unholy
No, don't say it, watch, wait
End of time, end of time, end of time
One last breath before we die
The sight of you intoxicates
Say your prayers, passed the time to confess
It's a game we never planned on winning, take us to rest
We fall, we break, we drown in fire
Lost inside in this dark desire
No love, no faith, just you and i
Dancing 'til the end of time, da-la-la-la-la-la, la-la-la
Ashes fall from blackened skies
All that's left is you and i
Drunk inside this love that's not mine
Da-la-la-la-la-la, la-la-la
End of time, end of time, end of time
半端なら K.O.
Half-ass deserves a K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
So be it, if you're light-hearted
開演準備しちゃおうか
Let's get ready for the show
泣いていても笑っていても愛してね
Cry or laugh, just love me okay?
ほら Say No
Come on, say no
低音響かせろ
Now let's bring the bass
なんかなくってつまらないこともあるでしょう
Don't know what to say, things tend to get boring
ロンリー論理のノート
Lonely logic note
ハンディ本気脱走
Handy serious escape
やんなちゃって泥に Bad
Can't take this anymore, it's bad taboo
ご法度だろうが溺れて墜ちて
Drown and drop in mud, it's about time
そろそろいっか
It's about time
もっと頑張って
Let's work harder
アガるまでもっと頑張って
Until I get excited
繋がろうひとりよりふたり
Let's connect, two is better than one
増えたら安心心配ないや Alright
More the people, more I'm relieved, alright
任せて don't mind
Alright, don't mind
波あり難題みんなで乗っかちゃえば
If we all ride the waves of problems
案外さくっと行いそう
Perhaps it's easy to solve
半端なら K.O.
Half-ass deserves a K.O.
開演準備しちゃおうか
Let's get ready for the show
泣いていても笑っていても愛してね
Cry or laugh, just love me okay
ほら say no
Come on, say no
低音響かせろ
Now let's bring the bass
今宵は暗転パーティー Woah
Tonight's a party in the dark
踊りだせ 踊りだせ 孤独は殺菌 満員御礼 Woah
Dance, dance, sanitize loneliness, full house, thank you
痛みまで おシェアで ここらでバイバイ let go
Even the pain, let's share it, time to say bye-bye, let go
どんな劣等感だて 即興の血小板で
Any complex, with a free-style platelet
抑え込んで 突っ込んで 仕舞い込んじゃうでしょ
Hold it, shove it, take it away
Up and down なテンション
Pumped up and down, pretty much stressed out
ねぇまいっちゃってんのの相当
Spit it out at once
ドバっと噴き出すのは 本音の独り言
Not really interested, don't really care
「別に興味ない」
Not really interested
「特にに関係ない」
Don't really care
塞ぎ込んで 舌端絶頂へ
Forget these feelings, I'ma say what I want
合図を奏でて PrrPrrPrr
Send signal, prr, prr, prr
ほら集まって夜行だ 鳴いていこうぜ
Let's come together, live the night, we be roaring
半端なら K.O.
Half-ass deserves a K.O.
Woah 踊りだせ 踊りだせ 孤独は殺菌 満員御礼 Woah
Dance, dance, sanitize loneliness, full house, thank you
痛みまで おシェアで 今宵も暗転パーティーだ Woah
Even the pain, let's share it, tonight's a party in the dark
またのお越しを きっと Woah
We look forward to serving you again
次回までお元気で ここらでバイバイ let go
Please take care until next time, bye-bye, let go
よお、おんなたれてるそのにいちゃん
Hey there, looking down, brother,
なんか辛いことあったんか？
did something painful happen?
俺でよけりゃ話してくんない？
If you're okay with me, won't you talk to me?
力になるぜ
I'll be your strength.
一体どんなことがあった？
What on earth happened?
それひでえ話だな兄弟
That's a crazy story, brother.
これをやるから元気出出しな
I'll do this, so cheer up.
金ならまた今度でいいさ
If you need money, it's fine next time.
シャンティ シャンティ シャンティ シャンティ
Shanti, shanti, shanti, shanti,
シャンティ ハッピー キャンディ
Shanti, happy, candy,
ハッピー ハッピー ハッピー キャンディ
happy, happy, happy, candy,
メニー メニー マニー
many, many, money.
眠らない夜のチャイナタウン
In the sleepless night of Chinatown,
その全てが縄張り
everything is a boundary.
老若男女問わずお客
Regardless of age or gender, customers,
使い終わったら捨てりゃいい
once used up, can just be thrown away.
今夜も来たのかい
Did you come tonight too?
お気に召したかい
Did you notice me?
代金はこれくらい
This is about the right amount.
え? え? え?
Huh? Huh? Huh?
払えないのかい
Can't pay?
ならばしょうがない
Then there's no choice.
君にぴったりの仕事があるからこっちについてきな
There's a job that suits you perfectly, so come with me.
焼かれた酒場 剥がれた女
A burned tavern, a peeled woman,
しゃがれた看板 掲げた大男
a hoarse signboard, a large raised man,
たかだかナイフでさされたよおじょ
stabbed with a mere knife.
気狂ってる目 散歩中
Mad eyes during a walk,
血を買って お前納得
buying blood, you understand.
提灯と リンドウ 咲かせた果て
The lantern and the gentian made to bloom at the end,
もう真の真を奏でたまえ
play the true truth now.
黙れ 座れ 黙れ
Be silent, sit down, be silent,
殴れ 殴れ 殴れ
hit, hit, hit.
縛れ 縛れ 縛れ
Bind, bind, bind.
ばらせ ばらせ ばらせ
Scatter, scatter, scatter.
今夜の華はどうだい
How about tonight's flower?
お気に召したかい
Did you notice me?
代金はこれくらい
This is about the right amount.
生きてれば お客
If you live, a customer.
死んでれば商材
If you die, merchandise.
滞りなく滞りなく回すビジネス
Smoothly, without a hitch, running the business.
どっちを向いてんだ
Which way are you facing?
やあ おんなたれてるそのじょおうさん
Hey there, looking down, queen,
なんか辛いことあったんか？
did something painful happen?
俺でよけりゃ話してくんない？
If you're okay with me, won't you talk to me?
力になるぜ
I'll be your strength.
一体どんなことがあった？
What on earth happened?
それひでえ話だな兄弟
That's a crazy story, brother.
これをやるから元気出出しな
I'll do this, so cheer up.
金ならまた今度でいいさ
If you need money, it's fine next time.
シャンティ シャンティ シャンティ シャンティ
Shanti, shanti, shanti, shanti,
シャンティ ハッピー キャンディ
Shanti, happy, candy,
ハッピー ハッピー ハッピー キャンディ
happy, happy, happy, candy,
メニー メニー マニー
many, many, money.
ひっくり返った路地裏散歩中
Strolling through the upside-down back alley,
散り失ってマイ納得
lost in the dust, fully convinced.
長者町 霊道 逆さだ果て
Chojamachi ghost road, upside-down end,
猛信 盲信 真を奏でたまえ
blind faith, blind faith, play the truth.
殴れ 殴れ 殴れや
Beat, beat, beat,
beat, beat, beat.
縛れ 縛れ 縛れや
Bind, bind, bind,
bind, bind, bind.
放せ 放せ 放せや
Let go, let go, let go,
let go, let go, let go.
放せ 放せ 放せや
Let go, let go, let go,
let go, let go, let go.
今夜の華はどうだい
How about tonight's flower?
お気に召したかい
Did you like it?
代金はこれくらい
The price is about this much.
生きてりゃ冒険家
If you're alive, an adventurer,
死んでりゃ所帯
if dead, a household.
滞りなく滞りなく殺しビジネス
Smoothly, without a hitch, the murder business.
どっちを向いてんだ
Which way are you facing?
はーい、というわけですごくかっこいいでしょ？
Hii, so isn't it cool?
こちらがロボ子の新衣装となります！
This is Roboco's new outfit!
見て、下から超かっこいいの！
Look, from below it's super cool!
どう？え、サングラス似合いすぎでは？
How is it? Eh, don't sunglasses suit me too much?
やばい、みんなが恋しちゃう？
Oh no, will everyone fall in love?
俺に惚れるとやけどするぜ？
Fall for me and you'll get burned, you know?
やべ、くそすぎる
Oops, that's way too cringe.
笑わないでね、笑うのやめてね
Don't laugh, please stop laughing.
はーい、というわけで見てこれ、かっこいいでしょ？
Hii, so look at this, isn't it cool?
なんかさ、指についんだけれどまだよく見えないね
It's on my fingers, but you still can't see it well.
まだ、まだよく見えないね
Still, still can't see it well.
え、おどりのときに必ず衣装からチェンジしたんだけど
Eh, I always changed outfits during the dance, but...
チェンジした瞬間、ちゃんとみんなわかった？
The moment I changed, did everyone understand properly?
沸いてくれましたー？
Did you get excited?
一瞬だったでしょ？
That was in a flash, right?
ふふっ、嬉しい！
Hehe, I'm so happy!
可愛い？かっこいい？
Cute? Cool?
ね、これなんか両方あるよ、かっこいいしかわいいよね。
You know, it has both. It's cool and cute.
プリチーでクールなの、これ。
It's pretty and cool, this.
いっぱい見て、いっぱい見て、足からちょっと見てく。
Look closely, look closely. Let's look from the feet up.
おっ、み、え？ やばい。
Oh... w-what? No way.
かっこよすぎるんだが。
It's way too cool.
見て、これロボット特有のさ、この
Look, this robot-specific...
人間だった多分めちゃ歩きづらいんちゃう？
If humans wore this, it'd be super hard to walk, right?
みんな多分歩けないよね、この靴。
Everyone probably couldn't walk in these shoes.
僕歩けるんだけどさ。
I can walk in them though.
ね、この靴で多分僕走ったら多分めっちゃ倍こけると思うから、歩きます。
If I ran in these shoes, I'd probably trip twice as much, so I'll walk.
どう？どう？
How is it? How is it?
はい、そして上からね、かっこよく決まって、ベルトあればあるだけいいですから、いっぱい着てもらえました！
Yes, and from the top, it looks cool and fitted. The more belts the better!
なんかマジで装飾品めっちゃかっこいい、キラキラ。金色のネックレス、風穴とか稲妻ついてるのかな？うん。
And seriously, the accessories are super cool and sparkly. A gold necklace...
あとなんか姿がちょっとおかしくなってるけど、僕の新衣装に合わせてロボ子さんがイヤリングにいたり、新しい丸眼鏡は
Also, my look is a bit funny, but matching my new outfit, Roboco-san is in the earrings.
ちょっとクールで装飾品もいっぱい付いてるし、何よりこのデッカイお団子、可愛いでしょ？ もふもふもふもふ、僕毛量多いの大好き！
It's cool with lots of accessories, and these huge buns! Fluffy fluffy, I love hair volume!
ね、え、このもふもふも可愛いよね。これ脱げるのかなって、ええ？
You know, this fluffy part is also cute. Can you take this off, huh?
だって指だってまだちゃんと見れてないもんね。
Because we haven't even really looked at the fingers yet, right?
脱げちゃうのかな、あとで。
Can we take it off later?
あとでのお楽しみにしてください！
Look forward to it later!
はい、ということで、え、でもライブ以来だよ、カラーライズ衣装来たの。かっこよかったでしょ？ ギャル。
Yes, it's been since the live wearing this colorized outfit. It was cool, right?
ね、めちゃめちゃ映えてるよね、うん。
You know, it really pops and looks great, yeah.
燃えちゃっファイアもね、もう早くね、リザベスが3Dモデル出る事も持ってるから、フェス！
And Lisabeth is also getting a 3D model soon, festival!
でも一緒に歌えてすごい楽しかった、ありがとうねみんな！
But singing together was super fun, thank you everyone!
はい、そしてお姉ちゃんとシャンティイタソラも歌いましたけれども、僕あげかっこよすぎる僕さ、一定そういますからね、ロボ子の低音が大好きすぎる民たち、うん、いつもありがとう、すっごい嬉しい、僕も気持ちよく歌えました。
And we sang Shanti and Itasora too, thanks to everyone who loves my low voice!
あ、ところでステージがなんか進行して、ドラゴン君が生まれてたの気づきました？
Oh, by the way, did you notice that the stage progressed and a dragon was born?
こいつ、どっから来たんやね、お前ね。ロボ子食われちゃいそうだよね。
This guy, where did you come from? Roboco looks like she's gonna get eaten.
うん、一回ロボ子をね、ドラゴンの口の中に入れてみようかね、ちょっと悩んだ。でも入れなかった、僕偉い！
I thought about putting Roboco inside the dragon's mouth, but I didn't. I'm great!
うわ、あいつの上に乗りがすぎるだろ、うん。
Wow, riding on top of that guy is way too much, yeah.
ということでですね、もう次の歌も歌いたいんですけども、せっかくね、この衣装なので、なんかゲストの中にめっちゃシナシあるやつがいるらしいんですよ。
And so, I want to sing the next song too, but someone among the guests is very China-style.
歌っちゃおうかな、ね、ドラゴン君、歌いたいよね、ね？
Shall we sing it? Hey Dragon-kun, you want to sing too, right?
あー、歌いたい！って言ってる気がするので。
Ah, since it feels like he's saying "I want to sing!".
じゃあ早速呼んでいきましょう！み、み、みどりー！
Then let's call them right away! Midori!
ロボ子久しぶり！ お誕生日おめでとう！
Roboco, long time no see! Happy birthday!
みゆちゃんありがとう！ みてみて、一緒に！
Miu-chan, thank you! Look, look, together!
めっちゃ可愛い！めっちゃ可愛い！一緒にいーあるふぁんくるぶ歌おう！
Super cute! Let's sing "1 2 Fan Club" together!
神戸中央区元町。駅前
Kobe, Chuo ward, Motomachi. By the station
今から ドキドキ ニーハオハインュー 講座
Starting today, the thrilling Ni Hao Hello course
大人、中高生、おばちゃんに 「・・・こんにちは」
To adults, students, and old ladies, "...Hello"
「ダメダメここでは あなたも“你好”!」
"No, no! Here you also say 'Nǐ hǎo!'"
マジで・・・テキスト 三ページ(早くも)
Seriously... textbook, page 3 (already!)
ここは とにかく羞恥心に勝つぞ
Anyhow, here I'll overcome shyness!
一万三千円の月謝は(安くない)
The 13,000 yen tuition (isn't cheap)
好好大家 ご機嫌いかが
Hello everyone, how are you?
『お母さん お馬さん』(媽馬)
"Mother, horse" (Māmǎ)
『ここはどこ 君は誰』(你是誰阿)
"Where am I, who are you?" (Nǐ shì shuí a)
大好きなワン・リーホンに
To my beloved Leehom Wang...
1、2、サンハイッ！
1, 2, three, go!
神戸中央区元町
Kobe, Chuo-ku, Motomachi.
(駅前)
(In front of the station)
今日から ドキドキニハオハーンュー講座
Starting today, a heart-pounding Ni Hao Chinese course.
大人、中高生、おばちゃんに 「...こんにちは」
To adults, students, and old ladies, "Hello."
「ダメダメここではあなたも“ニーハオ”！」
"No, no, here, you should use 'Ni Hao' too!"
マジで...。テキスト三ページ(早くも)
Seriously... the textbook is already on page 3.
ここはとにかく羞恥心に勝つぞ
Above all else, I must overcome my shyness.
一万三千円の月謝は(安くない)
The monthly tuition fee of 13,000 yen is not cheap.
好好大家 ご機嫌いかが
Hao hao daja, how are you doing?
「お母さん お馬さん」(媽馬)
"Mama (Mother), Ma (Horse)"
「ここはどこ 君は誰」(你是誰阿)
"Where am I? Who are you?"
大好きなワン・リーホンに 大好きだって言うため
To tell the Wang Leehom I love so much that I love him.
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地 いーあるふぁんくらぶ
Hi hi China, feeling like I'm in a dream, I-aru Fanclub.
だんだん 君と同じ言葉が 使えるね
Gradually, I'm able to use the same words as you.
ウォアイニ 言えるかな
Wo ai ni, I wonder if I can say it.
そこで知り合った女子高生(みかちゃん)
I met a high school girl there (Mika-chan).
曰く、台湾でジェイ・チョウのコンサート
She said, "Jay Chou's concert in Taiwan!"
それは行かなきゃだめだ
I have to go to that, no matter what.
(ところで)みかちゃん しれっと言ってるけど海外だよ？
(By the way...) Mika-chan, you say it so casually, but that's overseas, you know?
マジで...。エンジかかってるな(みかちゃん)
Seriously... you're really getting into it, Mika-chan.
ここはとにかく便乗して頑張るか
Here, above all else, I'll just jump on the bandwagon and do my best.
六万数千円の旅費も(安くない)
The travel expenses of 60,000+ yen are not cheap.
それでは再見バイト探さなきゃ
So, Zaijian, I have to find a part-time job.
「すみません、お嬢さん」(小姐)「これ一つ いくらでしょう」(多少錢)
"Excuse me, miss" / "How much is this?"
天国のレスリー・チャンに おやすみなさいって言うため
To say goodnight to the Leslie Cheung in heaven.
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地 いーあるふぁんくらぶ
Hi hi China, feeling like I'm in a dream, I-aru Fanclub.
だんだん 君の伝えたい気持ちが わかってくる
Gradually, I'm coming to understand the feelings you want to convey.
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地 いーあるふぁんくらぶ
Hi hi China, feeling like I'm in a dream, I-aru Fanclub.
だんだん 君と同じ言葉が 使えるね
Gradually, I'm able to use the same words as you.
憧れて 夢中になって 一ヶ月二ヶ月半年過ぎた
Longing for it, getting obsessed, one month, two months, half a year passed.
リア友は少し減ったけど それもしかたかないや
I lost a few real-life friends, but it can't be helped.
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地 いーあるふぁんくらぶ
Hi hi China, feeling like I'm in a dream, I-aru Fanclub.
だんだん 君と同じ言葉が 使えるね
Gradually, I'm able to use the same words as you.
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地 いーあるふぁんくらぶ
Hi hi China, feeling like I'm in a dream, I-aru Fanclub.
だんだん 君の伝えたい気持ちが わかってくる
Gradually, I'm coming to understand the feelings you want to convey.
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地 いーあるふぁんくらぶ
Hi hi China, feeling like I'm in a dream, I-aru Fanclub.
だんだん 君と同じ言葉が 使えるね
Gradually, I'm able to use the same words as you.
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地 いーあるふぁんくらぶ
Hi hi China, feeling like I'm in a dream, I-aru Fanclub.
だんだん 君の伝えたい気持ちが わかってくる
Gradually, I'm coming to understand the feelings you want to convey.
ウォアイニ 言わせてよ
Let me say "Wo ai ni".
ウォアイニ 言えるかな
I wonder if I can say "Wo ai ni".
龍
Dragon.
あ、龍！
Ah, dragon!
待って！
Hold on!
だって、だってあそこ僕に任されたんだもん！
Because that was left up to me!
ねえ、しかもさ、僕のこと、あの、「りゅうちゃん」って呼んでるよね、今日。
And besides, you call me "Ryu-chan,"
りゅうちゃん、りゅうちゃん。
Ryu-chan. Ryu-chan.
でも普段は「みどり」とか言うんですよ。
Usually you call me "Midori," right?
今日、今日だけ「りゅうちゃん」とか言って。
Just today, you said "Ryu-chan,"
りゅうちゃん！
Ryu-chan!
なんか幼馴染みづらで近づいてきたと思って。
Like you're calling me a little childhood friend, coming closer...
すごいドキドキしてます。
I was all doki-doki!
ほんと可愛くなっちゃった。可愛いこれ。どのポーズも可愛いこれ。
You got way too cute, seriously!
え、可愛いでしょう？
Cute, right?
んー。
Mm.
え、可愛い！
Cute!
りゅうちゃん、見てみて！
Ryu-chan, look, look!
えー、可愛い！
So cute!
きちゃった！
Come here!
ね、みんなも僕の部も褒めてあげてください。僕はあんまり褒めないので。
Hey, everyone, praise mine too! I don't praise mine much.
褒めろよ。
Praise me!
可愛い、本当に可愛い！
Cute, truly cute!
りゅうちゃん、もう一回ポーズしろ。
Ryu-chan, do another pose.
えっと、一緒にしよう？
Let's do it together.
しよう。
Do it.
きゅるん、きゅるん、かっこいい可愛い。
So cool, so cute!
最高やないの？
Isn't this the best?
いいじゃないですか。
Isn't it?
え、なんかポーズしようよ。
Let's do a pose.
希望があれば。
If you have any desire...
なに？と？パンチ？
What kind? Punch?
パンチ？うん。
Punch?
でもね、クソ雑魚パンチしたもんね。二人一緒に。
We did crappy punches, didn't we? Let's do it together.
超強いパンチ？
Super strong punch?
うん、かかってこいよ。
Come on, try fighting me!
最高、強そう……
So strong...
強そう！
So strong!
ほんとに強そうになっちゃった。
We really look super strong now.
なんか撃退したいリプライとかあったらね、これ使って。
If you have a reply to defeat someone, use this!
ね、使ってください。
Use it, please.
最強、強い、強そう。
Super strong!
強そう。
そう、私たち、私たち。
So, let's...
強そう。
So strong!
最強、強い、そう、強そうとポーズ。
Super strong pose.
え、見て、りゅうちゃん、見て。
Look, Ryu-chan, look at this!
可愛い、マジで可愛い！
So cute, seriously cute!
好きそう、素敵。
I want it, it's wonderful!
ね、ちょっとポーズはさておき、素敵よ。
Well, let's set aside the pose and look at the wonder.
やった！ポーズも褒めて！
I did it! Praise the pose too!
うん、適当なポーズも褒めて！
Praise my random pose too!
うん、めちゃくちゃいい感じでしょう？
It's a really good vibe, right?
強そう。
So strong!
おお、おお！
Oh, oh!
ちょっと可愛い！
A bit cute!
もう止まんないよ、もう褒め出したら。
I can't stop once I start praising!
やばい！
Yikes!
やばい、やばい、そんな嬉しい！
Yikes, yikes, I'm so happy!
今日呼んでよかった。
I'm so glad you called me today.
呼んでくれてありがとう。ありがと、ありがと。
Thanks for calling me, I'm so happy.
今日ね、まだ
Today, um...
締めの下手かもと思って。
I'm bad at closing, I think.
がんばってね！
Do your best!
可愛い！
Cute!
ねえ、あいつマジでで雑談んだよ！
Hey, she really put effort into it!
はい、というわけで、緑でした！
So, that was Midori!
りゅうちゃんでもちろんなんでも呼んであげてください。
You can call me Ryu-chan or whatever you like!
じゃあ、ロボ子も次がんばりますんで、ふう、ぽち！
Roboko will do her best next time too! Pochi!
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうなshy love
A shy love that looks like it will disappear like bubbles
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡のはじけるチャイナ
China where the bubbles burst
ももこは誕生日おめでとう！
momoko, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はるちゃん、まちるの世界へようこそ！
Welcome to the world of Harucha and Machiru!
ともこもうまっくろになっちゃった。
Tomoko's stomach became pitch black!
ともこまっくろ。
Tomoko is pitch black.
ともこもうまいこと。
Tomoko, wait a minute, wait a minute.
行ってきます。
I'm going.
wow wow wow 我愛你
I wanna do it to you
きみに我愛你
I love you to you
我愛你 我愛你
I love you, I love you
あなたに
To you
いとも簡単に陥る我愛你
I love you, falling into it so easily
我愛你 我愛你
I love you, I love you
純情なmon amis
Pure-hearted mon amis
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうなshy love
A shy love that looks like it will disappear like bubbles
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡のはじけるチャイナ
China where the bubbles burst
密かに
Secretly
重度の後悔に終わる我愛你
I love you, ending in severe regret
我愛你 我愛你
I love you, I love you
そんなやつ
That kind of guy
やめちまいなチャイナ
Just quit it China
チャイナ・チャイナ・チャイナ・アドバイス
China China China advice
もうわたしの虜になっちゃいなよ
Just become my prisoner already
チャイナ・アドバイス
China advice
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうなshy love
A shy love that looks like it will disappear like bubbles
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡のはじけるチャイナ
China where the bubbles burst
表情に言外に潜む我愛你
I love you, hiding in the nuances of your expression
我愛你 我愛你
I love you, I love you
そう曖昧に
Yes, ambiguously
憾の限界に挑む我愛你
I love you, challenging the limits of agony
我愛你 我愛你
I love you, I love you
ねえそろそろ
Hey, it's about time
やめちまいなチャイナ
Just quit it China
チャイナ・チャイナ・チャイナ・アドバイス
China China China advice
いい加減に大人になっちゃいなよ
Just grow up already
チャイナ・アドバイス
China advice
i wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうな shy love
A shy love about to vanish like bubbles
i wanna do it do it yeah
泡のはじける チャイナ
China, where bubbles pop
wow wow wow 我愛你 きみに我愛你
Wow wow wow, wo ai ni, wo ai ni to you
我愛你 我愛你 あなたに
Wo ai ni, wo ai ni, to you
いとも簡単に陥る 我愛你 我愛你 我愛你
Easily falling for you, wo ai ni, wo ai ni
純情な mon amis きみに 我愛你
My pure mon amis, wo ai ni to you
我愛你 我愛你 密かに重度の後悔に終わる 我愛你 我愛你 我愛你
Wo ai ni, secretly ending in severe regret...
そんなやつ やめちいな チャイナ
Give up on a guy like that, China!
はるちゃん！うれしい！一緒に歌って！
Haru-chan! Yay! Sing with me!
楽しかった！
It was fun!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとう、こちらこそ！
Thank you, right back at you!
はるちゃんさ、ここで出ないの？ 今日
Haru-chan, aren't you appearing here today?
そう、ここがおうち
Yeah, this is home.
すごいよね、これね
It's amazing, right?
え、すごいよね！というわけで今日は
Eh, it's amazing! So today...
はるちゃんがゲストに来てくれました！
Haru-chan came as a guest!
こんにちはー
Hello~
はるちゃんです
It's Haru-chan.
はるちゃんがさ、すごいさ、みんなも「え、そこ設定あるの？」って多分別々思われると思うよね
Everyone probably thinks, "Eh, is there a setting for that?"
一応さ、ポストとかでさ、スター、そう、お土産…
Well, like on posts, star, yeah, souvenirs...
お土産ね
Souvenirs, right?
そう、お土産をね、あげたの。そしたら実ハルちゃんからも僕はやお土産をもらってる
Yeah, I gave her souvenirs. And actually I get souvenirs from Haru-chan too.
確かにあげたわ。でもそれはポストしてない
That's true, I gave. But I didn't post that.
そう、なんだかんだね、結構ね、遊んでたりもしたからね
Yeah, we've been hanging out a lot anyway.
そう、今回はお呼びしました！どうでしたか？
So this time we invited her! How was it?
どうでしたか？私に来てりゅ……
How was it? Coming to me...
え、みんなに聞いてるの？あんなに
Eh, are you asking everyone? Like that.
え、でもどうだった？一緒に歌って。
Eh, but how was it? Singing together.
え、超楽しかった！
Eh, super fun!
え、うれしい！僕も楽しかった！
Eh, yay! I had fun too!
ね、初めて歌ってさ、うんうん、歌ったよね！歌ったよ！そうだよね！歌った！
You know, singing for the first time, yeah yeah, we sang! We sang, right? That's right! We sang!
こういう場所でね！
In a place like this!
すごいよね、これね
It's amazing, right?
だってさ、こうあいだが結構さ、近いからさ、「あ、絶対これ似合うやん」と思って今回はチャイナアドバイス呼びました！
Because our vibe is pretty close, I thought "Ah, this definitely suits you" and called China Advice!
あ、ここが決めたの？
Ah, you decided this?
そうなんだ！
Is that so!
え、光栄なの？でしょ？
Eh, is it an honor? Right?
すごい！光栄な！
Amazing! An honor!
はるちゃんがさ、珍しいんだよ。僕のことロボ子って呼ぶの。
It's rare for Haru-chan. She calls me Roboco.
え、そうなんだ？
Eh, is that so?
そう、珍しいんだよね。
Yeah, it's rare.
あんまりいないの、マジで。
Not many people do, seriously.
さっき聞いた時びっくりした！
I was surprised when I heard earlier!
そう、もうナチュラルにずっとロボ子なの。
Yeah, it's naturally always Roboco.
そうずっとロボ子
Yeah, always Roboco.
え、逆に何？何が？え？
Eh, conversely what? What? Eh?
ロボちゃんとかロボさんとか先輩とか？
Robo-chan, Robo-san, or Senpai?
あ、ねえ、それちょっとよくわかんない
Ah, hey, I don't really get that.
先輩なんだよ、ロボ子！
I'm your senpai, Roboco!
え、そう、先輩なんだよ一応！
Eh, yeah, I'm technically senpai!
これ本当はやりたかったけどできない、忘れてた！ハート作ります！ハート！
I really wanted to do this but couldn't, I forgot! Let's make a heart! Heart!
え、いけそうじゃない？あ、みんな、みんな写真撮って！みんな写真撮って！
Eh, looks doable right? Ah, everyone, everyone take pictures! Everyone take pictures!
いやでも、いい感じやん
Well, but it's a good vibe.
え、かわいい！え、どう？これ、新しい衣装なんですけれども
Eh, cute! Eh, how is it? This is a new outfit, but...
超かわいいと思います！
I think it's super cute!
え、はるちゃん的におすすめのポーズとかあったら撮ってほしいんだけど
Eh, if Haru-chan has any recommended poses, I want you to take it.
え、ちょっとあれやって、上目遣い
Eh, do that, looking up from under.
上目遣い?
Looking up from under?
カメラ…かわいい、かわいい！はるちゃんいっぱい遊んで！かわいい！いっぱい遊ぼう！
Camera... cute, cute! Haru-chan, play a lot! Cute! Let's play a lot!
でも手はゴツいんだよね！そうだ、めちゃめちゃかっこいい！見て！
But the hands are bulky! That's right, super cool! Look!
え、でも好きでしょこういうの？うん、いいね。
Eh, but you like this kind of stuff? Yeah, nice.
ゴツい、かっこいい！これめっちゃ高い！高いんだ！おお、そうそうそう！めっちゃ高い！多分、パパが作ってくれた！
Bulky, cool! This is super expensive! It's expensive! Oh, yeah yeah yeah! Super expensive! Probably, Papa made it for me!
パパもすごいな！うん、パパもすごいな！
Papa is amazing too! Yeah, Papa is amazing too!
おだんごもさ、超かわいいから！
The hair buns too, are super cute!
え、おだんごかわいいでしょ？見て！
Eh, the hair buns are cute, right? Look!
モウジョウがめちゃめちゃあるんだよロボ子
There are so many decorations, Roboco.
後ろから見るとすごいね！
Looking from behind it's amazing!
全部かわいい！
All cute!
え、やった！オールパーフェクトじゃん！パーフェクト！
Eh, yay! All perfect, right? Perfect!
はるちゃんこれ途中でやってたの気づいた？これ、歌中？やってたの気づいた？
Haru-chan, did you notice I was doing this midway? This, during the song? Did you notice?
なんか、こっち見てやってたよね、しかも。「気づけー」って。はんめせんでやっちゃってた
Like, you were looking this way doing it, moreover. Like "Notice me!". Doing it with half-closed eyes.
そうだんだ…
Is that so...
おめでとう本当に！
Congratulations truly!
なんか…え、何? なんかすごい…あれだよね、反対に「おめでとう」ってすごく丁寧に言ってくれるからさ
Like... eh, what? Like it's amazing... right, conversely you say "Congratulations" so very politely.
おめでとうなんだもんって。え、もう嬉しい、ありがとう！
Because it's congratulations. Eh, I'm so happy, thank you!
次も…うん。
Next too... yeah.
まだ早いか？
Too early?
いいよ！
It's fine!
大丈夫か？
Is it okay?
大丈夫！
It's okay!
え、まだね、いっぱいあると思うからさ、頑張ってね！頑張る！
Eh, there's still a lot, so do your best! I'll do my best!
はるちゃんじゃ、応援してね！
Haru-chan, cheer for me!
応援する！
I'll cheer!
見てるね！
Watching!
見てて！ありがとう！
Watch! Thank you!
バイバーイ！はるちゃーん！
Bye-bye! Haru-chan!
またねー！
See you later!
バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
はるちゃんって結構マイペースなんですよ。
Haru-chan is pretty at her own pace.
i wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうな shy love
A shy love about to vanish like bubbles
i wanna do it do it yeah
泡のはじける チャイナ
China, where bubbles pop
どいつもこいつもなんだかやっぱノーテンキ
Everyone, everyone, still so carefree,
気になるあの娘も悩みはきっとあるでしょ?
The girl you like has worries too, right?
雑多で半端な憂鬱どもは群れをなし
Jumbled, half-baked depressions swarm together,
アタマの中はぐちゃぐちゃさ
My head is an absolute mess.
ドンマイ弊害 育児のない方程式
Don't mind obstacles, equations without upbringing,
イケナイイケナイ 事柄なんてないから
Because there's no such thing as a taboo.
イー・アー・サン・シ じゃんけんでさあおいで
1, 2, 3, 4, come on with rock-paper-scissors,
ウー・リュウー・パク・デ 手裏剣まかれてく
5, 6, 7, 8, shuriken are being scattered,
キミはもうハイスピードだな
You're already at high speed,
ありゃまこりゃま お待たせだな
Oh my, oh my, you've kept me waiting!
ハッチャでメッチャなドラマ 派手にドラが鳴るよ
A wild, chaotic drama, gongs ring out loudly!
いい・いい・許婚っきゅん I love youなのだ
I-i-fiancé, it's an "I love you",
四六時中 愛をちょうだい はて?
Give me love around the clock, huh?
いい・いい・一か八っきゅん
I-i-all-or-nothing,
i・哀・逢・愛 罠ろっきゅー
I-sorrow-meeting-love, trapping heartbeat,
1/2じゃもの足りない
1/2 isn't nearly enough!
それでも結局 見えないアイツの胸の内
Even so, I can't see into that guy's heart,
押し付けましの見栄取りもいらないから
No need for forced posturing or vanity,
先輩後輩ヤンキー雀鬼 関係ない
Senior, junior, yankee, gambler, it doesn't matter,
いざ真剣に勝負
Let's have a serious showdown!
君がもしも その気なら boy meets girl が始まりそうなら
If you're in the mood for a boy meets girl story,
まだ見ぬ技繰り出す 僕らってば so sweet だな
Unleashing unseen skills, we're so sweet, right?
手際が良くても顔が同じだけ
Even if we're quick-handed, our faces are just alike,
喋ちゃもくれなの修羅場
A scene of carnage with no idle chat,
派手に銅鑼が鳴るよ
Gongs ring out loudly!
意味深な like you 曖昧な愛より直球
A "like you" with hidden meaning, direct over vague love,
しいのごの言わずに察してちょうだい
Don't complain, just figure it out!
待て! いちびるな 天罰! 鼻血ぶーなのだ
Wait! Don't get carried away! Divine punishment! A nosebleed!
自分の意志はどんなもんなんじゃい
What is your own will anyway?
いい・いい・許婚っきゅん I love youなのだ
I-i-fiancé, it's an "I love you",
四六時中 愛をちょうだい はて?
Give me love around the clock, huh?
いい・いい・一か八っきゅん
I-i-all-or-nothing,
i・哀・逢・愛 罠ろっきゅー
I-sorrow-meeting-love, trapping heartbeat,
1/2じゃもの足りない こんなんじゃさあ
1/2 isn't enough, with something like this,
会いたいかもしれない 毎晩キスとテンパ足りないや
Maybe I want to see you, kissing every night and my tension isn't enough,
偶然のつぼえ うらめしらま
Accidental pot, envious face,
出会い無情 面会回転
Fleeting encounters, rotating visitations!
はい、ということで! いいの? づっきゅんでした! どうでしたか?
Yes, and that was "Ino? Tsukkyun!" How was it?
え、シルエットのさ、ここここ、こうじゃなかった? ポンポンってしての(笑)
Um, the silhouette's... right here, wasn't it like this? Patting like bon, bon (laughs)
結構お気に入りポイントです! はい、どうだった?
It's quite my favorite point! Yes, how was it?
かわいいでしょ? 改めて新鮮でしょ?
Cute, right? Refreshing, right?
ねー! みどりともはるちゃんともね、歌えてうれしー!
Right?! I'm so happy I could sing with Midori and Haru-chan too!
まさかの「えっ」って思ってる人が出ててもね、めっちゃ多かったと思うんだけど、(笑) お呼び出ししました今回は。うれしいです。
And I called them up this time, even though many of you were like "Eh?!" I'm so glad.
さあ、というわけで、もう結構経ったね。うーん。
Well then, quite a bit of time has passed already. Yeah.
なんかそろそろうずうずしてる人たちがいっぱいいる気をするの。
I feel like there are a lot of people getting restless about now.
うずうずうずうずうずうずうずうずうず… 僕が一番うずうずしてる(笑)
Restless, restless, restless... I'm the most restless one here (laughs).
はい、というわけで、待てができないので、えー、ご紹介したいと思います! 誕生日といえば…
Yes, so since I can't wait anymore, um, I'd like to introduce them! Speaking of birthdays...
誕生日グッズー! 今回の誕生日グッズはこちらー!
Birthday merch! This time's birthday merch is right here!
はい、久しぶりにタペストリーを出します!
Yes, for the first time in a while, I'm releasing a tapestry!
まず1つ目、B2タペストリー! こちらイラストもね、とってもクールな僕なんですけれども、え、シャガム先生に描いていただきました!
First one, a B2 tapestry! The illustration is of a very cool me, drawn by Syagamu-sensei!
え、あ、これ「りゅう」違いとかやめてね。「りゅう」…うっ。お前も好きだし、お前も好きだぞ。みんな愛してる「りゅう」です。(笑)
Um, oh, stop saying it's a different "Ryu". Ryu... ugh. I like you too, and I like you too. It's "Ryu" that loves everyone (laughs).
え、めっちゃかっこいいよね! 強そうな龍と強そうな僕。かっこいいでしょ?
It looks super cool, right? A fierce-looking dragon and a fierce-looking me. Cool, right?
そして2つ目は、なんと! おなかいっぱいぺちゃお! 餃子皿!
And the second one is, amazingly! The "Stuffed Full Pechao" Gyoza Plate!
なんと、こちらロボ子先生が描いてくれました! えへへへへ。
Amazingly, Roboco-sensei drew this one! Hehehehe.
見て、なんかすごいもう…
Look, it's just amazing...
いっぱい食べる君満々の沼にハマってるロボ子とロボさ。
I've fallen into the swamp of Roboko and Robosa,
めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょう。
who are all about eating plenty.
このお皿を使っていっぱいね、餃子なり何なり食べてください。
Please use this plate to eat lots of gyoza and whatever else you like!
お腹いっぱいになると幸せになるのでね。
Because getting full makes you happy.
はい！
Yep!
そして次は？
And what's next?
ご飯を食べたら喉も渇く。
After eating your meal, you'll get thirsty.
ちあーず！グラスですね。
It's the 'Cheers!' glass.
ビール入れてもいいし、
You can pour beer in it,
お茶入れてたっていいし、
tea, or whatever you like,
ジュース入れてたっていい！
even juice would be great!
美味しいものどんどん飲みましょう。
Let's drink lots of delicious things.
こちらもなんとロボ子先生が描いてくれました高精度なのだ！
And amazingly, Roboco-sensei drew this high-precision design!
可愛すぎる。
It's too cute.
こんなウインクされたらいっぱい飲んだってね、いいですから。
If she winks at you like that, drinking a lot is totally fine!
ぜひご飯と飲み物を食卓に使ってくださいまし！
Please use these for your meals and drinks at the table!
今度僕も配信で使ってみたいと思うので、ぜひチェックしてみてください。
I'd love to use it on my stream sometime, so be sure to check it out.
そしてまだまだあります。こちらっどーん！
And there's still more. Here it is, ta-da!
はい、僕の大好きなぬいぐるみ！
Yes, my absolute favorite plushie!
本日も可愛いものができました。
We've made something adorable today as well.
見て。お座りしてんの、今回の、お座りぬいぐるみ、チャイナロボさむね、ここにいますよ。
Look! This time it's a sitting plushie, and China Robosamu is right here.
はい。
Yes.
今回はお座りのぬいぐるみなので、そのまお部屋に飾ってもいいし、お出かけ連れても一緒に写真撮りやすいのかなと思います。
Since it's a sitting plushie, you can display it in your room or take it out for easy photo ops.
はい、いっぱい色んなところに連れてってあげてください。
Please take it along to all sorts of places.
大切にしてね。無くさないでね。置いとかないでね。たくさん買っとって、いいんだからね。
Treasure it, don't lose it, don't leave it behind... and you can buy lots of them, you know!
そして、ボイスも出ます。
And voice packs are coming out too.
今回は僕VS竜。
This time it's 'Me vs. Dragon'.
マジ竜の名前ささだのまらんのよね。
Seriously, I can never get enough of the dragon's name.
緑だっていいし、竜だっていいし、ドラゴンくんだっていいし、ドラちゃんだっていい、なんだっていい！
Midori is fine, Ryuu is fine, Dragon-kun, Dora-chan, anything is fine!
なんでもいい！
Literally anything is fine!
いいよね。ね？
Right? Right?
はい。君に襲いかかる竜に可愛さ勝負を挑む僕のお話。
Yes. A story where I challenge the dragon attacking you to a cuteness contest.
きゅっ。
Kyu!
はい、どんなお話かはぜひ買って聞いてみてください。
Yes, please purchase and listen to find out what kind of story it is.
さあ、最後にこちら！
Now, finally, this!
はい、今回のフルセット購入特典についてお話しします。
Yes, I'll talk about the full set purchase bonuses this time.
まず一つ目、数量限定版が今回はあります。
First of all, there is a quantity-limited version this time.
数量限定版は僕の直筆サインと白押し野糞、複製メッセージ入りのポストカードになります。
The limited edition comes with my autograph and a foil-stamped, duplicate message postcard.
はい、ぜひ今回は僕のこの配信が終わると同時にカードがオープンしますので、そのタイミングでぜひ狙ってみてください。
Yes, the cards will go live right as this stream ends, so please try to aim for them at that timing.
スタートダッシュの準備は
Are you ready for a
いいかー！
flying start?!
ぜひゲットしてくださいね。
Please be sure to get yours.
もちろん通常版もあります。
Of course, there is also the regular version.
通常版は僕の直筆サインはないんですけど、白押しリーのサインとメッセージのポストカードがついてきますので、ぜひゲットしてください。
The regular version doesn't have my direct autograph, but it comes with a foil-stamped signature and message postcard, so please grab one!
そして、まだフルセット購入特典にはボイスが付きます。
And additionally, the full set purchase bonus includes voice tracks.
一つ目、キミと竜と夜の空。
First, 'You, the Dragon, and the Night Sky'.
こちらはハンバーボイスの少し後の時間帯のお話で、なんと時間軸は続いております。
This is a story set a little after the standalone voice, and the timeline actually continues.
ハンバーボイスはね、別に単体でも楽しめますけど、特典ボイスも合わせると、え？あの後の続きがあるの？って楽しめるのでぜひ聞いてほしいです。面白いよ。
You can enjoy the standalone voice on its own, but combined with the bonus voice, you'll be like, 'Wait, there's a continuation?!' so I really want you to listen. It's fun!
そしてなんと、今回はじゃーん！タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、2024年から9月から発売がされたホロライブおいでざるカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚ついてきます！
And what's more, ta-da! As a full set bonus for the talent premium goods, you get 1 card usable in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME released starting September 2024!
同行するカードはホロライブプロダクションおひざるショップで購入されたお客様のみの対象となります。
This card is exclusively for customers who purchased from the hololive production official shop.
今回特典につくのはゲームで1枚だけ使用でき、推しをアピールすることができるカード、推しホロメンカードです！
The bonus card this time is an oshi holomember card—a special card you can use once in the game to appeal your oshi!
みんな欲しいショクレ 一枚今しか買えないロボちゃんは買うべき強いよ！
Everyone wants this, right? You can only buy one right now, so Robo-chan is a must-buy and super strong!
はい、というわけでカードの詳細や遊び方については、多分僕を僕から聞くより、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの公式ホームページで確認したほうが分かりやすいと思うので、ぜひチェックしてみてください。
So, regarding the card details and how to play, rather than hearing it from me, it's probably easier to check the official hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME website, so please check it out.
はい、登場するカードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご了解ください。ノーイングリッシュソリー！
Please note that the appearing cards are only available in Japanese. No English, sorry!
うん、グッズのカードオープンはこの後配信終了後になりますのでみんな！体験して買ってね！いっぱい買っていい！
Yep, the card opening for the goods will be right after this stream ends, so everyone, make sure to get yours and buy lots!
そして！この後はなんと！
And what's coming next...
なんと初めての！ねんぎ…あ、あ、あ、え…アンコールライブがありまーす！
is our very first encore live!
叫んでは、
Even if I scream,
でも飲まれるな！
nobody can hear me!
最近お酒飲んでない！
I haven't been drinking recently!
アンコールでアンコールに似てるんだわ。
It's like an encore of an encore!
はい、ということで、なんと今回はね、アンコールライブがありますので、
Alright, so we're having an encore live this time!
アンコールライブはね、みんながずっと僕に立って欲しそうだった
Since everyone's been standing for me, hoping for this,
あの歌を歌っちゃおうかなと思ってるので、楽しみにし待っててください！
I want to sing that song, so please look forward to it!
なんかせっかくだからね、写真撮影会とかね、ロボサと密な空間でいっぱい見せちゃおうかなって
Since we have the chance, I want to show off lots of things,
思ってます！メンバーのプレゼント、ありがとうございますね。みんな、ぜひ見ててください！
like the photo session and more! Thanks for the member presents, everyone, please check them out!
はい、というわけで、ロボさん
Alright, Roboco...
早いけど、次が最後の曲になっちゃうみたいです。
it's fast, but it looks like next will be the final song.
僕はもう9歳。9歳になったロボさん、ここまで成長を見届けてくれてありがとうね。
I'm already 9 years old now. Thank you for watching me grow up to 9!
これからもまだまだ僕は成長していくので、一緒に末永く楽しんでいきましょう！
I'll keep growing from now on, so let's enjoy a long time together!
最後の曲は、初めにちらって言ったけど、
For the final song, I mentioned it briefly at the start,
ドラゴンくんに乗りたいな。一緒に頑張ってくれる？ねえ、ドラゴンくん！
but I want to ride a dragon! Won't you try your best with me, Dragon-kun?
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく
Bit by bit, I'm falling under your spell
その眩しい笑顔に
Your smile's all I need to see to know we'll
果てない闇から飛び出そう Hold my hand
Leave this endless darkness, saying, "Hold my hand!"
君と出合ったとき
Back when you first came into my life,
子供の頃大切に想ってた景色を思い出したんだ
I recalled a special place that I held close to my heart as a child.
僕と踊ってくれないか
Won't you lead me in a dance down this winding road?
光と影の Winding Road 今でもあいつに夢中なの？
Are you still obsessed with him, even on this winding road?
少しだけ振り返りたくなるような時もあるけど
Sometimes I want to turn around and see the things I've passed,
愛と勇気と誇りを持って闘うよ
but with love on my side, with courage and pride, I'll fight!
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく
Bit by bit, I'm falling under your charm
この宇宙の希望の片隅
You'll keep me and all the world far from harm
きっと思いは永遠を手に入れたい
Bring hope to everyone; take in your hands eternity
ZEN ZEN 気にしないふりしても
Even when it seems that I don't need you,
ほら君に恋している
Just know that I am in love with you!
果てない闇から飛び出そう Hold your hand
Leave this endless darkness. Won't you come along with me? Hold your hand!
怒った顔も疲れている君も好きだけど
Even when you're angry or tired,
あんなに飛ばして生きて大丈夫かなと思う
I think everything will be okay living so recklessly.
僕は...何気ない行動に振り回されてる sea side blue
I'm swept away by casual actions... sea side blue.
それでもあいつに夢中なの？
Even so, are you still obsessed with him?
もっと聞きたいことがあったのに
There was so much more I wanted to ask,
二人の会話は車の音にはばれて通りに舞うよ
but our conversation was drowned out by the traffic and vanished away.
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく
Bit by bit, I'm falling under your spell,
自分でも不思議なんだけれど
though even I find it strange myself.
何かあると一番に君に電話したくなるんだ
Whenever something happens, you're the first person I want to call.
ZEN ZEN 気のないふりしても
Acting like I don't care at all,
結局君のことだけ見ていていた
I end up focusing only on you.
海の彼方へ飛び出そうよ Hold my hand
Let's fly out beyond the sea, hold my hand!
結局君のことだけ見てた
In the end, I was only looking at you.
海の彼方へ
Let's fly away toward the sea,
飛び出そうよ Hold my hand
Hold my hand
Oh my heart!
みんなロボさー
Everyone, Robosa!
今日は見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for watching today!
このあとはなんと！
And after this, guess what!
メンバー限定で歌いまーす！
I'll be doing a members-only live!
遊びに来てねー！
Come hang out with me!
グッズもめっちゃかわちいから
The merch is super cute too,
ゲットしてくれよなー！
so make sure to grab some!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
なんか君も遅いね ドラゴン君
You're kind of late too, Dragon-kun.